React created virtual dom and updates the real dom only at places that they differ
Uses JSX (which uses Babel to transform code to JS)
In JSX there are no if/else, for, forech statement
Installin bootstrap trough consule "npm i bootsrap@version" and than we need to import it
One component can return only one node

1. create component as loosly coupled and reusable
2. make code clean
3. delete resources after component ends

ctr+d to find net name occurances
ctr+space display suggestion
imrc - snipet for import component
ccc - snipet fro create class
sfc - snipet for stateless functional component
check element abbriviation html visual studio
check jira
ctr+p and then @ to nvigate to elements into component
shift+ctr+p to open palet, then search >wrap and type the name of the tag
alt+Cursor click - to show multiply cursor
112

State is a special property with data that component needs
State can have anytype of properies
Setting atributes in the tags have similar but different name from HTML
We can use {} to render value dinamicly
When we want to render dinamicly, we need to define function that return result that we want
and then use that result in the return statement form the component
We render array with map method
When we render array we need to give elements unique id using key atribute
When using event handler, it is good practice to use arrow function because of "this"
Directly changing the state it is not working because react is creating virtual dom
Updating the state in react is done with function setState({newState})
Passing arguments in eventHandler is done with arrow function who is calling
method that accept the argument
Main script is index.js and we are importing all necessary elements there
Named export elements require to be imported in {}
Default exports can be without {}
All the class have a property called props that 
include every properties that are passed down from the parent
It have special prop called children. We are passing content between opening and closing tags
Props includes data that we give to component, state is data local to that component
Props is readonly and we cant modiy it
Single source of truth - when components rely on single state and they are passing
data trough props. The update of state it is done trough raising event
When we want to sync multiple components, they need to have the same parent
and the parent should hold the state.
When component has only rendenr method (no state, no eventhandlers, no other methods) 
we can convert it to SFC (stateless functional component)
if we want to use props in SFC we need to pass that as a argument into the function
usually it is good idea to use object destructuring when we are using SFC

LifeCycle Hooks - method that are called in order automaticly durrning lifetime of component
Often are used:
Mount - constructor(used most to initialize something), 
	render(renders all children also), 
	componentDidMount(used most for ajax call)
Update - render(all the components are rendered and that comparet to the actual dom), 
	coponentDidUpdate (can acces the prevProps and prevState. we can compare the new state with old state)
Unmount - componentWillUnmount (method called just before removing component from dom
	   it is used for clean up to avoid memory leaks)

Typechecking in react:
PropTypes is used to check the properties that are passed to the components.
we should include this at the end of every loosly coupled component that we are build
with this, if some proprs are not passed in the correct form, we will get warning in console  
it is instaled separatly => i prop-types@versionNumber
When making reusibe component, make sure to avoid thigh coupling 
(importing services, avoid using stric proeprties, avoid state,use general naming convention)

npm i lodash@version_name - wokrking with plain js
npm i react-router-dom@version.name -  working with routing
npm i querry-string@version.name - to extract values from query strings

To add routing in React application we need to insatl react-router-dom. 
then we need to import it in the index file and wrap the app component with browserRouter
next step is to register the routes in the wraped component. Import Route component and set
the two props: path and component
Avoid using a tag in react when using links. Instead impot component Link and use that.
when using a the bundle.js is download every time. With Link the bundle is not downloaded
Router component has his own 3 props: history, location, match
match - mainly to extract or add values from route
location - mainly to extract query strings
history - for programatic navigation

Passing custom props to component from Router we are using rendern then 
arrow function passing props as an argument and destructure props
Optional parametars to be avoided. Use query strings instead
Query strings are in prop location.search 

In React avoid working with document object. Instead using reference with React.creatRef()
